citizen.co.za 2009-11-01

# The Citizen: Privacy Policy

The short version...

Below you can read the full text of our privacy policy, in 3p3 format, which is an Internet standard now used for privacy policies.

The short version is as follows:

1\. We do not send email. Any email. At all.

2\. Should you decide to register at this site, we do not share the information gathered. With anyone. At all.

The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Web page, not shared with other organizations for commercial or any other purposes.

3\. We cannot identify you from the information we gather.

4\. We do not make the e-mail addresses of those who register at our site available to other organizations or within our own company for any purpose whatsoever.

5\. With respect to Ad Servers: To try and bring you offers that are of interest to you, we have relationships with other companies that we allow to place ads on our Web pages. As a result of your visit to our site, ad server companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information. For further information, consult the privacy policies of www.google.com

6\. From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice.

If our information practices change we do not make use of any information gathered for any purpose not laid out in the policy under which it was gathered.

7\. Customers may request their information be removed from our systems by e-mailing us at the address below, calling us at the below telephone number, writing to us at the address below.

With respect to security: We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

The full text of our privacy policy

About Us

This is a privacy policy for The Citizen 1978 (Pty) Ltd. Our homepage on the Web is located at http://www.citizen.co.za. The full text of our privacy policy is available on the Web [here](http://www.citizen.co.za/index/marketing.aspx?pDesc=4391,1,29). Users may go to for information on how to opt-in or opt-out of use of their information.

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by mail at the following address:

The Citizen

PO Box 40462

Industria

Johannesburg, Gauteng

2093 

South Africa

You may contact us by e-mail at [webmaster@citizen.co.za](mailto:webmaster@citizen.co.za).

You may call us at +27 (0)11 28-6000.

Dispute Resolution and Privacy Seals

We have no privacy seals or other assurance mechanisms.

Additional Information

This policy is valid until 1 Jan, 2007 at 12:00:00 GMT+02:00.

Data Collection

P3P policies declare the data they collect in groups (also referred to as "statements").

This policy contains 3 data groups. The data practices of each group will be explained separately.

Group "Basic information"

We collect the following information:

* Click-stream data

* HTTP protocol elements

* Search terms

* User's interaction with a page or resource

This data will be used for the following purposes:

* Completion and support of the current activity.

* Web site and system administration.

* Research and development.

This data will be used by ourselves only.

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

Data collected from all Web users: access logs, and search strings (if entered).

Group "Cookies"

We collect the following information:

* HTTP cookies

This data will be used for the following purposes:

* Research and development.

* One-time tailoring.

This data will be used by ourselves.

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

Cookies are used to track visitors to our site, so we can better understand what portions of our site best serve you.

Group "User Information"

At the user's option, we will collect the following data:

* Birth year, month, and day

* User's Gender

* Demographic data

* Current location data

This data will be used for the following purposes:

* Completion and support of the current activity.

* Web site and system administration.

* Research and development.

This data will be used by ourselvess.

The data in this group has been marked as non-identifiable. This means that there is no reasonable way for the site to identify the individual person this data was collected from.

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

Demographic research of web use

Cookies

Cookies are a technology which can be used to provide you with tailored information from a Web site.

A cookie is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system.

You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it.

Our site makes use of cookies. Cookies are used for the following purposes:

* User targeting

* Research and development 

Compact Policy Summary

The compact policy which corresponds to this policy is:

CP>"NOI CURa ADMa DEVa TAIa OUR NOR STP IND UNI COM NAV INT DEM LOC"

The following table explains the meaning of each field in the compact policy.

Field Meaning

CP> This is the compact policy header; it indicates that what follows is a P3P compact policy.

NOI No identifiable information is collected, so no access is possible.

CURa The data is used for completion of the current activity.

ADMa The data is used for site administration.

DEVa The data is used for research and development.

TAIa The data is used for tailoring the site.

OUR The data is given to ourselves and our agents.

NOR The data is not kept beyond the current transaction.

STP The data is kept for the stated purpose only.

IND The data will be kept indefinitely.

UNI Unique identifiers are collected.

COM Computer information is collected.

NAV Navigation and clickstream data is collected.

INT Interactive data is collected.

DEM Demographic and socioeconomic data is collected.

LOC Current location information is collected.

The compact policy is sent by the Web server along with the cookies it describes. For more information, see the P3P deployment guide at [http://www.w3.org/TR/p3pdeployment.](http://www.w3.org/TR/p3pdeployment)

Policy Evaluation

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6 will evaluate this policy's compact policy whenever it is used with a cookie. The actions IE will take depend on what privacy level the user has selected in their browser (Low, Medium, Medium High, or High; the default is Medium. In addition, IE will examine whether the cookie's policy is considered satisfactory or unsatisfactory, whether the cookie is a session cookie or a persistent cookie, and whether the cookie is used in a first-party or third-party context. This section will attempt to evaluate this policy's compact policy against Microsoft's stated behavior for IE6.

Note: this evaluation is currently experimental and should not be considered a substitute for testing with a real Web browser.

Satisfactory policy: this compact policy is considered satisfactory according to the rules defined by Internet Explorer 6. IE6 will accept cookies accompanied by this policy under the High, Medium High, Medium, Low, and Accept All Cookies settings.
